Yulia Goriunova UX designer | Product designer

Stamp 4, Blackrock, co. Dublin

Design it's not just 'pictures', but actively engaging in user-centric problem solving

Contacts

+353 83 0705869
yulia.zuk.v@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/yulia-zhuk-v/

Behance

Dribbble

Portfolio

https://uxfol.io/iuliiaG password: Yuliasportfolio

Profile

My successful career has given me considerable experience as a seasoned UX/UI designer.

I bring to the company better user experience in B2B and B2C, specializing in e-commerce and UCaaS. Designing for both web platforms and mobile applications. Regarded as passionate about all my work, particularly in problem-solving, which has consistently provided a quality outcome on behalf of my employers and their customers.

Skills

Research: usability testing, interviews, preference tests, a/b tests, surveys, benchmarking, CJM, information architecture, rapid prototyping, user flow, website analytics, affinity mapping, personas.

Design: interaction design, building interactive components, creating design systems, pixel perfect icons. Familiar with material guidelines, human interface guidelines, carbon design system, and other design systems, WCAG.

Prototyping tools: Figma, Sketch, XD, HTML/Css, Adobe Creative Suite, Marvel, Principle.

Experience

Lead UX/UI designer Health and Help August 2024 – present

Volunteer as UX/UI designer in a charity organisation that builds clinics and provides medical help in central America.

Leading the team of 3 junior UX/UI designers, helping with designing interfaces for the website and donor dashboard to simplify and improve donors experience.

Senior UX/UI designer <u>Blueface Comcast Business company</u> February 2020 – May 2024

Blueface: A Comcast Business Company is a technology business specializing in unified communications as a service. to carriers and businesses of any size, anywhere in the world.

- Integrated user research seamlessly into project workflows, enriching decision-making processes.
- Introduced analytics tools to our strategic decision-making framework.
- Maintained continuous communication and dialogue with developers, ensuring responsiveness to project needs.
- Transitioned to Figma for streamlined workflows and improved collaboration with developers.
- Established comprehensive guidelines, featuring elements and examples, providing clear directives on their application. Prioritized and executed enhancements to product accessibility, ensuring it meets WCAG standarts, emphasizing our commitment to inclusivity and user-centric design.

Working effectively within an excellent UX design team. I consistently contributed to a diversity of projects, such as the UCaaS platform, video conferencing solutions, mobile applications, and web applications. As a focused UX designer, my responsibilities involve working closely with project managers, the product team of 5, business customers, and software engineers. This effective collaborative approach ensures a comprehensive understanding of user needs and seamless integration of design solutions into the development process.

UI/UX designer at freelance February 2019 – February 2020

During this period, I contributed to projects such as:

Collaborated on a courier aggregator for Decathlon e-commerce (UX/UI),

working with various stakeholders and designing 42 screens for different conditions and user journeys.

- Contributed to the UX/UI design of a CRM for Decathlon's ship-from-store operations.
- Worked on a SaaS platform for project management (UI), collaborating with business analysts and web developers to create a UI guide and design 56 screens based on material design guidelines.
- Provided graphic design for advanced emails for Decathlon, creating the final email using Stripo.

Ul designer at ABBYY December 2017 – February 2019

Collaborated with product managers, the marketing team, and web developers to craft layouts and graphic content for web pages. Get experience in creating pixel perfect icons and graphics in Adobe Illustrator.

Conducted UX analysis on websites to identify and address experience-related issues. In conjunction with developers, actively contributed to:

- Redesigning the searching and search results page to enhance user experience.
- Reworking a template for all banners to improve information accessibility across various screen sizes.
- Offering UI solutions for responsive websites and updating elements within a comprehensive design system.

UX/UI designer at Decathlon January 2015 – October 2017

Working in e-commerce gave me a lot of experience with data-driven design in a fast paced environment.

During my work at Decathlon, I managed collaboration with third-party contractors to successfully launch website personalization. This initiative resulted in x2 user activity and conversion rates.

As a UX/UI designer in the e-commerce department at decathlon.ru, my primary

responsibilities included:

- Designing and developing web pages for services, promotions, and informational purposes
- Creating and developing email templates and promotional emails.
- Analyzing, formulating, and testing hypotheses, including AB tests for optimization.
- Use Google Analytics to evaluate the success of the created campaigns.
- Forming and coordinating an outsourced web development team.
- Executing various graphic designs.
- Engaging in web design activities.

Education

Product designer, Artem Gorbunov Design Bureau August 2015 – June 2016

During this course, I've dedicated time to studying visual design, interface design, negotiations, and problem-solving. Additionally, I've gained practical experience by working directly with the Art Director on a project for four months. This invaluable experience has shifted my perspective on the responsibilities of a designer, emphasizing the role as not just "drawing pictures" but actively engaging in user-centric problem-solving.

Engineer's degree, Moscow State University of Instrument Engineering and Computer Sciences (MGUPI) 2007 – 2012

The course has provided a solid foundation for my future career by covering essential aspects such as design, arts, information technology, and production. My studies in these areas have equipped me with a well-rounded skill set, laying the groundwork for a successful and fulfilling professional journey ahead.

Courses and certifications

- User Research, Interaction Design Foundation 2021
- User Experience, Interaction Design Foundation 2020
- UX design, Openprofession 2018
- Advertising graphics and matte painting, Skillbox 2018

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Computer Training Center «Specialist» at Bauman $\mbox{MSTU} 2014 2015$
- Kanban methodology, intensive 2018

Languages

English, Russian.